# **OLUYEMI OLUSUSI**

# **EXPERIENCED SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

📞 +2348066417364 🖂 yemiwebby@gmail.com 💡 Abuja, Nigeria 🔗 https://www.yemiwebby.com.ng/

#### **CAREER PROFILE**

Software engineer with over 4 years of experience in applying practices, methods and tools that help improve software quality and developer productivity. Adept at providing technical direction to software developers, working hand-in-hand with customers and project managers to achieve business goals. Over the years, I have built Bespoke software (Web and mobile) that has helped several startups improve their businesses.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Junior Web Developer**

May 2016 - Oct 2016

Greenwich Media Limited

- Fixed bugs on existing websites and implemented enhancements that significantly improved web functionality and speed.
- Built and design responsive layout for web applications

# Software developer

Nov 2016 - Jul 2017

Century Data Integrated Services Limited

- Worked with a team of other Software Developers to build robust and scalable REST API for easy integration with third party applications.
- Maintained existing legacy project and implemented other features to improve the relevance of the application for users

### **Software Engineer**

Jul 2017 - Aug 2018

Taxaide Technologies

- Researched coding and database concerns to resolve non-functional applications issues.
- Generated a reusable software library by refactoring and extracting software code from one project and packaging it for use across multiple projects.
- Worked as a fullstack developer and was involved in the concepts and full implementation of web applications for tax remittance purposes.

#### **Freelance Software Developer**

Apr 2018 - Jan 2019

MobileTM

- Rebuilt an existing web applications and implemented new features according to software requirement
- Enhance the web application to integrate properly with payment gateway and other third party libraries

#### **Lead Software Engineer**

Jan 2019 - Present

Needle Technology

 Mentored and trained personnel on policies and procedures regarding systems, programming and troubleshooting.

#### **INDUSTRY EXPERTISE**

- Documentation
- Technical Guidance
- Software Development

- Software Debugging
- API Design
- · Database Design

## **SOFTWARE SKILLS**

- Technical Guidance
- Software Development
- Laravel
- ReactJS
- Nest.js
- Nginx

- API Design
- · Database Design
- Symfony
- VueJS
- HTML/CSS

#### **EDUCATION**

# **BEng, Telecommunications Engineering**

2014

Federal University of Technology, Minna

CGPA: 3.89 / 5.00 (Second Class, Upper)